<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Unamed Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[ ]]></description><link>https://unamedblog.azurewebsites.net</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 10:06:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Customary First Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[Welcome to my new blog! I’ve been meaning to get this up and running for a while now… but life gets busy. But here it is! After a lot of…]]></description><link>https://unamedblog.azurewebsites.net/customary-first-post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://unamedblog.azurewebsites.net/customary-first-post/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Welcome to my new blog!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to get this up and running for a while now… but life gets busy. But here it is! After a lot of thought, testing and planning, I decided that a static site was something that I really wanted to build as my personal blog. I have tried heavier CMS platforms in the past, namely WordPress, and while it served its purpose, it never really clicked with me. It wasn’t raw enough for me. That’s when I came across GatsbyJS and I knew I had found the one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GatsbyJS is essentially a static site generator based on React componenents. At my core, I love tinkering with new cutting edge tech and I felt that a static site, while simple, would allow me to do that. It also allows me to host this thing wherever I choose. There is no database or fancy server config to mess around with, which ultimately means that I can go with flow when it comes to hosting. I’m also planning to offer some site building and hosting services pretty soon, using GatsbyJS to create modern, fluid, offline available websites for those who want them. So stay tuned for that ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason I chose a static site over a bigger CMS system (although I CAN still use that if I want to, due to the awesomeness that is GraphQL), is that I really want to learn and play with decentralised systems for hosting content. An example of this would be using IPFS as an alternate means to view this blog (If you haven’t seen IPFS yet, check it out here). Another thing that I’d really love to attempt is setting up a comments system that uses a federated identity, so that you can essentially use any of the new decentralised social media platforms (Mastodon, Numa etc.) to post a comment and then that comment would be available through those services as well, maybe with a hashtag of the blog title that gets automatically added to your comment. Expect this site to change and update over the coming months as I experiment with new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically what I’m saying is that I’m a massive geek and static sites are really cool!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>